A Guide to the Farrier Family Papers, 1894-1972
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Box 34, 1915-1972 (Bulk, 1940-1969) (Box 34)
  - Farmers Home Administration, December 1971-January 1972.
  - Rader, Dolan and wife, Janaury-March 1972.
  - Rose, Lillie B., May 1972.
  - Lawyers Title Insurance Corp.
  - Lucas, L. L. and Clinton, January 1937-June 1942.
  - Millitrons vs. Jones, June 1947-May 1949.
  - Lucas, C. A., November 1934-July 1941.
  - Snidow, H. E., et al vs. Mary B. Snidow Caldwell, et al, March 1967-July 1968.
  - State Highway Commission of Virginia vs. Florence S. Hoge, et al, February-November 1960.
  - N & W Railway Co.--Killey land, July 1972.
  - N & W Railway Co.--General, February 1952-March 1954.
  - N & W Railway Co. vs. Nancy Minnick, June-July 1960.
  - N & W Railway Co. vs. Vaught, L. D. (administrator), September 1956-May 1958.
  - N & W Railway Co.--General, May 1949-July 1968.
  - Doyle vs. N & W Railway Co., November 1957-March 1958.
  - Hays, S. R. vs. N & W Railway Co., October 1946.
  - Alexander, John J. vs N & W Railway Co., December 1957-February 1958.
  - N & W Railway Co.--Celanese purchase, December 1958-March 1960.
  - N & W Railway Co. vs. James E. Bruce, June 1961-November 1963.
  - N & W Railway Co.--Land from Ray H. Snider and wife, April 1960-August 1967.
- Box 35, 1919-1971 (Bulk, 1930-1950) (Box 35)
  - N & W Railway Co.--Land from Emil R. Amelong, April-August 1967.
  - N & W Railway Co.--Land from Sherman L. Raines, April-August 1967.
  - N & W Railway Co. vs. McWilliams, February 1963-March 1966.
  - Ingram-Taylor Furniture, Inc. vs. N & W Railway Co. and James H. Whittaker, August 1970-February 1971.
  - Pedigo-Southwood Addition, November 1941.
  - Pedigo, W. D., March 1939-May 1940.
  - Raines Estate Land, April-November 1948.
  - Rich Creek Water Co., November 1941-January 1942.
  - Rich Creek Development Co., December 1919-August 1929.
  - Fort Branch, January 1941-July 1943.
  - H. W. Hale Estate, February 1932-July 1947.
  - Snidow, Frank P., April 1931-July 1946.
  - Snidow vs. Snidow, April-November 1947.
  - McDonald Land, October 1944-March 1956.
  - Standard Lime and Stone Co., 1953.
  - Standard Lime and Stone Co.--Kanode Land, November 1944.
  - Standard Lime and Stone Co., 1954.
  - Shumate, G. W. estate, May 1937-March 1946.
  - Smith, W. R., October 1942.
  - Standard Lime and Stone Co.--E. M. Henderson land tract, October 1944-April 1948.
  - Snidow vs. Snidow, April 1946-March 1947.
  - Shumate, A. E., December 1934-November 1944.
  - Williams, Eliza P.
  - Strader, W. E. estate, August 1944-October 1945.
  - Tinsley heirs, October 1944-August 1950.
  - Vaught, Virgil V., October 1946-February 1947.
  - Wheeler, R. V. estate, October-November 1940.
  - Lyda Williams vs. E. N. Williams, December 1929-July 1940.
  - Williams, John F. estate, February 1934.
  - Williams, Claude B and wife, July-September 1941.
  - Wood, Mrs. Bertha, July 1934-April 1941.
  - Wheeler, Wm. R. estate, June 1939-September 1943.
  - Woodson, W. O. titles, September 1944.
  - Warren, James L., trustee vs. E. J. Hudson, July 1939-February 1945.
  - Wheeler, A. R., January 1943-April 1945.
  - Woodyard, N. Y. estate, June-August 1945.
  - Walker and Taylor, July 1934-April 1935.
  - Walker and Taylor, February 1932-April 1935.
  - Wills vs. Wills, January-April 1945.
  - Wright, Walter R. and wife, May 1945-December 1946.
  - Williams, Don L, May 1945-December 1946.
  - Williams, M.D. and others, April 1941-February 1949.
- Box 36, 1910-1959 (Bulk, 1920-1949) (Box 36)
  - Correspondence, small claim suits, land sales, and other legal matters: Hazel B. Keffer; Roy Dunford; G. W. Nowlin; J. W. Hale; W. H. Nickels; N & W Railway Co. annual passes; S. B. Nelson; Radford Finance Corp.; A. K. Hylton. June 1934-January 1951.
  - Correspondence, small claim suits, land sales, and other legal matters: C. J. Presby (Prealey?); H. H. Powell; Martin Williams; Leonard Freeman; W. D. Payne; B. W. Porterfield; O. K. Phleager; Bank of Pocahontas; L. L. Prescott; J. P. Price; J. B. Pulliam; J. H. Price; Pulaski Grocery Co.; Pearisburg Virginian; Cleopatra Porterfield; Personal Services, Inc; Mrs W. L. Piper; A. J. Porterfield; Mrs. W. P. Poindexter; R. F. Pritchard; Princeton Motor Co.; Pembroke Mutual Telephone Co.; A. M. Pyne; First National Bank of Peterstown; Mattie Spangler; Sarah Ella Poterfield; Carrie Page; S. A., J. M., and R. W. Patteson; G. H. Parent Co.; Walter M. Perdue; C. W. Peek and Co. September 1934-March 1948.
  - Correspondence, small claim suits, land sales, and other legal matters: Southeastern Finance Co.; T. G. Porterfield; Office rent receipts for M. P. Farrier; Roundtree Corp. vs. W. N. Hurley; Richmond Office Supply Co.; Rawls-Dickson Candy Co.; Chas. S. Roller, Jr.; Mrs. Lacy Riggs; B. S. Ratcliff; A. W. Robertson; The Repass Adjustment Bureau; Frank Turner Shop; Richmond Adjustment Bureau; the Roanoke Hardware Co.; Roanoke Photo Finishing Co.; Miss Mary Rogers; Bruce Rader; W. H., H. M., and W. P. Reynolds; T. J. Pearson; Hugh Reid; Chief of delinquent tax section for Com. of Virginia; J. P. Royall; Harry H. Roberts; Ronceverte Small Loan Co.; R. D. Rowley. July 1934-May 1948.
  - Correspondence, small claim suits, land sales, and other legal matters: Kate A. Simpson; A. E., E. J., and J. L. Straley; Atlee L. Smith; F. H. Stansill; Southwest Loan and Discount Co., Inc.; H. P. Sartin; D. C. Spangler; Thomas B. Stanley. June 1937-January 1953.
  - Taylor, George P., December 1928-March 1936.
  - Lucy B. Vaught, September 1936-May 1944.
  - Correspondence, small claim suits, land sales, and other legal matters: E. E. Sarver from Isaac Williams; M. L. and F. S. Williams; J. C. Williams vs. Commercial Credit Co.; W. G. Williams; S. S., G. L., and C. B. Williams; Donald L. and C. K. Williams. February 1937-November 1946.
  - Narrows, First National Bank of, FHA loans, June 1937-February 1941.
  - Bank of Giles County, July 1928-July 1938.
  - Saxon Lime and Lumber Co., August 1910-January 1927.
  - Potomac Joint Stock Land Bank, May 1925-March 1927.
  - Pearisburg Hatchery Corp., February 1928-January 1929.
  - First National Bank of Pearisburg, March 1924.
  - Pence, H. L., February-October 1925.
  - D. C. Pearson, June 1926-January 1927.
  - Henry V. Pierce, March 1926.
  - Mrs. Tom Perdue, Janaury 1927.
  - Bank of Pearisburg, April-October 1925.
  - Pembroke Mfg. Co., January-February 1924.
  - Pearson estate, March-May 1926.
  - Perdue vs. Gearheart, April 1920-April 1921.
  - Pearson, T. J. estate, August 1919-March 1927.
  - D. C. Pearson, et al, July-August 1924.
  - Rich Creek Power Co., February 1927.
  - Rich Creek Hardware Co., September 1924-May 1930.
  - Robinson, R. W., June 1914 and October 1925.
  - 54 court briefs concerning cases before the Virginia State Court of Appeals at Wytheville or Richmond, October 1911-October 1959.
- Box 37, 1913-1941 (Bulk, 1920-1939) (Box 37)
  - Bland County Lumber Co. vs. D. M. Bruce et al, August 1933-September 1941.
  - Bland County Lumber Co. vs. D. M. Bruce, May 1924-April 1939.
  - Bland County Lumber Co.--Right of Way.
  - Builders Mfg. and Supply Co., Inc., May 1928-September 1930.
  - A. T. Shumate vs. N. G. Spangler et al, June 1929-November 1931.
  - Highway Commission vs. John King, February-June 1931.
  - Fannie Dabney vs. Richard Dabney, May-July 1930.
  - Birchfield Options, February 1930-January 1932.
  - Franklin Real Estate Co., June 1930-September 1931.
  - M. T. McArthur, January 1931-March 1932.
  - Mary A. Fleeman vs. E. F. Fleeman, October 1930-June 1932.
  - Manganese Products Co., December 1933-February 1934.
  - Secondhand list, March 1931-January 1934.
  - Johnson, S. L., March 1930-May 1933.
  - Appalachian Electric Power Co., August-September 1934.
  - Morton, Glenna vs. Coca Cola Bottling Co., August-December 1931.
  - Morehead vs. Hart, February 1913-October 1931.
  - Kelley, F. D. vs. H. B. Johnson et al, September-October 1930.
  - J. A. Johnston, et al vs. Whittaker, March-July 1931.
  - Dodds vs. Lafon, February-July 1931.
  - Coburn, L. B. vs. Woodyard, December 1931-March 1932.
  - Bolling vs. Bradley, January-September 1931.
  - Woodson, W. O., December 1931-April 1932.
  - NRA, July-August 1933.
  - Marshall vs. Marshall, June 1930.
  - W. A. Farrier vs. Cord, April 1928-March 1933.
  - Ledger of legal fees charged by firm, February 1920-January 1924.
  - Spencer L. Johnston, October 1934-March 1935.
  - C. H. Campbell cs. K. S. French, et al, March 1933.
  - St. Elizabeth Hospital, June 1926-February 1929.
  - Hoilman, C. A. vs. Mary C. Painter, September 1931.
  - Brogan vs. Lilly, June 1927.
  - Danner vs. Salyer, March 1928-August 1929.
  - Golden, Paul vs. Virginia Hardwood Lumber Co., et al, November 1928-October 1929.
  - Fuller, R. L. vs. Arthur Elliott, et al, September-December 1930.
  - Mechanicsburg, Bank of vs. Melvin, May-October 1930.
  - Moore Lumber Co., August 1927-January 1929.
  - C. W. Kelly vs. Grady Robertson, March 1930-February 1931.
  - King vs. Turk, March-July 1929.
  - Jones, E. W. vs. W. W. Shumate, September 1927-July 1930.
  - Peters vs. Peters, April-September 1930.
  - Mrs. Mary S. Pulliam vs. Commonwealth, June 1929.
  - N & W Railway Co. vs. Ira W. Peters, admin., December 1929.
  - F. P. Snidow vs. W. H. Thompson, admin. of Ercie Jennell's estate, January-May 1923.
  - Songer vs. Songer.
  - Tuggle, J. C. vs. Conley, Hopkins, and Robertson, November 1927-March 1930.
  - Commercial Credit Co. vs. W. H. Venable, November 1930-January 1931.
  - Commissioner of Accounts, August 1940-August 1945.
- Boxes 38 & 39 (Typed on a single list in original inventory), 1911-1968 (Box 38-39)
  - Copies of wills, title searches, contracts, deeds, etc. written by A. L. Farrier, July 1953-August 1968.
  - Check book and cancelled checks, February 1966-January 1969.
  - Ledger LI Shroder Farm (record of expenses kept by A. L. Farrier), March-November 1962.
  - Ledger LII G. A. Shumate estate, February 1950-July 1963.
  - Audit of the Bank of Giles County, Pearisburg, 1960.
  - One box of old deeds and cancelled notes, October 1911-June 1953.
- Boxes 40 & 41 (Typed on a single list in original inventory), 1913-1969 (Box 40-41)
  - Check books, February 1922-January 1954.
  - Ledger XVII (accounts), September 1913-May 1915.
  - Ledger XVIII (accounts), May 1919-December 1925.
  - Ledger XIX (collection cases handled by Martin Williams), June 1920-March 1925.
  - Ledger XX (cases and fees received), June 1920-December 1927.
  - Ledger XXI (P. F. St. Clair estate), March 1914-September 1915.
  - Ledger XXII (contains only one short entry concerning stock holder's meeting), March 1951.
  - Ledger XXIII (accounts), May 1913-December 1915.
  - Ledger XXIII (money received by Williams and Farrier), May 1931-May 1932.
  - Ledger XXIV (collection suits, fees, disbursement of funds), October 1921-September 1940.
  - Materials concerning court suits, deeds, collection suits, court briefs, photograph negatives, checks, and correspondence, April 1921-May 1969.
- Box 42, 1902-1946 (Box 42)
  - Ledger XLII (fees received), September 1927-December 1932.
  - Ledger XLIII (suit settlements), November 1903-April 1936.
  - Ledger XLIV (fees received), January 1924-March 1931.
  - Ledger XLV (M. P. Farrier accounts and fees received), June 1914-February 1933.
  - Ledger XLVI (fees received), February 1932-December 1944.
  - Ledger XLVII (Saxon Lime and Lumber Co. accounts), August 1919-August 1928.
  - Ledger XLVIII (records concerning estates), September 1902-December 1938.
  - Ledger XLIX (G. W. Shumate estate records), December 1924-March 1931.
  - Ledger L (J. J. Cole Timber operation), July 1926-October 1932.
  - Check books and cancelled checks, November 1932-July 1946.
  - Stock book--Bland County Lumber Co., Inc., December 1919-March 1931.
  - Correspondence, notebooks, legal papers.
- Boxes 43-44 (Typed on a single list in original inventory), 1919-1929 (Box 43-44)
  - Files, deeds, contracts, and loose correspondence from the office of Williams and Farrier. The majority of material deals with small claim collection and damage suits, but there are also a few land sales, divorce suits, and contract disputes. Files run in rough alphabetical order from V. P. Anderson to F. E. Williams.
- Boxes 45-46 (Typed on a single list in original inventory), 1911-1972 (Box 45-46)
  - Ledger XXXII (Estate of Miss Francis St. Clair), September 1944-May 1946.
  - Ledger XXXIII (M. P. Farrier estate), June 1934-April 1958.
  - Ledger XXXIV (fees received), January 1943-June 1946.
  - Receipt Book (money received by A. L. Farrier), October 1966-June 1970.
  - Ledger XXXV (cash received by A. L. Farrier), August 1046-August 1949.
  - Ledger XXXVI (Daniel E. Hale estate), December 1927-January 1929.
  - Checks/cancelled checks by A. L. Farrier, Janaury 1945-April 1972.
  - Loose deeds, correspondence, contracts, court suits, and materials pertaining to estate settlements and other legal matters, March 1911-October 1972.
  - Income taxes of A. L. Farrier, 1966-1968.
- Boxes 47-48 (Typed on a single list in original inventory), 1897-1938 (Box 47-48)
  - Ledger XXV (Collection record), June 1917-April 1924.
  - Ledger XXVI (fees received), April 1897-April 1919.
  - Ledger XXVII (Unnamed estate with heirs G. W. Meredith, Lacy Meredith, Helen E. Hendrickson), January 1932-January 1935.
  - Ledger XXVIII (collection record), October 1926-January 1938.
  - Ledgerss XXIX, XXX, XXXI (Shumate estate), April 1915-January 1926.
  - Honaker and Feeney (4 files), August 1920-February 1927.
  - Correspondence to/from M. P. Farrier regarding legal practice, May 1904-May 1932.
  - Correspondence (Shumate estate), December 1924-March 1927.
- Boxes 49-50 (Typed on a single list in original inventory), 1903-1940 (Box 49-50)
  - Ledger XXXVII (Pearisburg Law Building Co. Inc.), January 1911-July 1921.
  - Ledger XXXVIII (The Merriman Co., Inc.), June 1903-June 1913.
  - Ledger XXXIX (Acme Lumber Co., Inc.), August 1922-January 1930.
  - Acme Lumber Co., Inc., Checkbook, June 1926-September 1940.
  - Ledger XL (Williams and Farrier fees collected), January 1911-May 1924.
  - Ledger XLI (Crockett Mining Company), June-October 1918.
  - Honaker and Feeney settlement, Fenruary 1923-September 1925.
  - Correspondence (M. P. Farrier, Martin Williams, and the Camp Mfg. Co.), January 1921-July 1924.
  - Notebooks, scratch pads, checkbooks, and cancelled checks.
  - Fount Johnston estate, March 1917-September 1930.
- Box 51, 1895-1972 (Box 51)
  - Ledger I (Big Stony Railway Co.), October 1903- October 1920.
  - Ledger II (Lawyer's collection docket), January 1902-February 1918.
  - Ledger III (Bland Lumber Co.?), August 1919-March 1925.
  - Ledger IV (New River Lime Co.), April 1928-December 1931.
  - Ledger V (collection record), February 1929.
  - Ledger VI (M. P. Farrier, receiver for Honaker and Feeney), May-December 1923.
  - Ledger VII (receiver for Honaker and Feeney), May 1923-January 1931.
  - Ledger VIII (G. A. Shumate estate), January 1917-April 1921.
  - Ledger IX (Narrows Milling Co.), January 1922-January 1927.
  - Ledger X (receivership of Pembroke Mfg. Co.), January 1925-August 1928.
  - Ledger XI (Town of Pearisburg treasurer), September 1922-September 1934.
  - Savings account record in the name of John M. St. Clair, guardian for Frances St. Clair, September 1944-February 1946.
  - Two manuals for the Virginia Senate and House of delegates, 1922, 1952.
- Box 52, 1893-1946 (Box 52)
  - Ledger XII (Williams and Farrier), October 1918-December 1934.
  - Ledger XIII (chancery causes referred to M. P. Farrier), November 1894-September 1903.
  - Ledger XIV (fees received by M. P. Farrier), March 1893-July 1924.
  - Ledger XV (fees received by Farrier and Farrier), March 1939-November 1942.
  - Ledger XVI (fees received by Farrier and Farrier), January 1939-July 1946.
  - Loose materials consisting of checks, deeds, court cases, and correspondence, February 1910-July 1946.
- Boxes 53-54 (Typed on a single list in original inventory), 1918-1930 (Box 53-54)
  - Correspondence received by Williams and Farrier concerning clients, court suits, land sales, and legal matters, 1918-1930.
- Box 55 (Maps) (Box 55)
  - 1. Little Stoney Game and Fish Preserve. Mountain Lake. Hand drawn map.
  - 1a. "Indicates line agreed on by Court." 1940.
  - 1b. Map of Lake Hotel Corp. Property of Mountain Lake, Giles County.
  - 2. Standard Lime & Cement Co.
  - 2a. Map of tract Kilbalton Plant.
  - 2b. Standard Lime and Cement Co.
  - 3. Addair property, Lurich, Giles County (known as trace no. 7 on the map of Bell Point).
  - 3a. Map of James Addair Estate, Bell Point.
  - 4. Map showing inclusive survey of the Johnston-Stader tract and the J. Raling L. Johnston tract (blueprint).
  - 5. Topographic map of the state of Virginia, U. S. Geological Survey, 1928.
  - 6. Topographic map, Giles County and surrounding counties, U. S. Geological Survey.
  - 7. Map of Airport View, Giles County (blueprint).
  - 8. Bland County Lumber Co., handdrawn map.
  - 8a. Map of the survey made for Bland County Lumber Co. lying in Bland and Giles counties in what is known as "The Flat Top Region" embracing the total watershed of Dismal or Silver Creek (blueprint).
  - 9. Map of King Heights, addition to Pearisburg (blueprint), 1939.
  - 10. Map showing the lots laid out for F. P. and J. J. Snidow, Pembroke, VA.
  - 10a. Plat showing Elizabeth Snidow lots.
  - 11. Map of the farmland of J. H. Spanlger's heirs, Rich Creek, Va. (original drawing).
  - 12. Map of the Fletcher farm, 1.5 miles east of Narrows, Giles County on State Highway #100 (contour map on verso).
  - 13. Plat showing Edgewood Development, Ripplemead, Giles County.
  - 14. U. S. Geological Survey map of Virginia-West Virginia (including Montgomery and Floyd counties).
  - 15. Survey map of Hoge's Chapel, Va., 1968.
  - 16. Survey, "James Hoge in the ejectment suit of W. B. Honaker," 1906.
  - 17. Tracing cloth map, Kenepper and Good, Bland County.